Good evening ladies and gentlemen. A
very warm welcome to ICIC Lumbard
General Insurance Company Limited Q4 and
FI 2025 earnings conference call. From
the senior management we have with us
today Mr. Sanjiv Mantri MD and CEO of
the company Mr. Gopal Balchandran CFO
Mr. Girish Nyak chief technology and
health underwriting and claims Mr. Sep
Kuradyia chief corporate solutions
international bank assurance Mr. Alan
Singhi, chief retail and government
business. Mr. Korov Aurora, chief
reinsurance underwriting and claims for
property and casualty. Please note that
any statements comments are made in
today's call that may look like
forward-looking statements are based on
information presently available to the
management and do not constitute any
indication of any future performance as
future involves risk and uncertainties
which could cause results to differ
materially from the current views being
expressed. As a reminder, all
participant lines will be in the
listenon mode and there will be an
opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation concludes. Should
you need assistance during the
conference call, please signal an
operator by pressing star then zero on
your touch on phone. I now hand the
conference over to Mr. Sanjief Mantri,
MD and CEO, ICIC Lumbard General
Insurance Limited. Thank you and over to
you.
Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earning conference
call at IC Lumbar General Insurance
Company Limited for quarter 4 and
financial year 2025.
Let me give you a brief overview of the
trends we observed in the economy as
well as the industry followed by an
overview of the business. Post this our
CFO Mr. Gopal Walachandran will share
the financial performance of the company
for the quarter and the year ended 31st
March 2025.
The the GDP growth for the quarter ended
December 2024 stood at 6.2% versus 5.6%
6% for the quarter ended September 2024.
As per the data released by Moxy, high
frequency indicators like eway bills,
toll collections, diesel consumption,
and GST collections during quarter 4 of
financial year 2025 are all indicating
positive economic conditions. Further,
MOPS has revised the fullear GDP
estimates to 6.5% on Feb 28, 2025 versus
6.4% 4% published on Jan 7, 2025.
Let me not dwell on certain industry
trends which can have an impact on the
general insurance industry at large. As
indicated during the last quarter, the
government expenditure remained flat
which impacted the commercial line
segment growth for the current quarter.
However, we have started seeing an
uptick in government spending towards
capital expenditure in past few months.
This may be a positive for the
commercial line of business.
For the auto industry, we had seen a
growth in rural market in Q3 of 2025.
Specifically for two viller segment at
12.7% and the tractor segment at 20.1%.
As reported by FAR. However, in quarter
4, 2025, we have seen a degrowth of 1.9%
for the two-heer segment and a degrowth
of 4.6% for the tractor segment. This
indicates a softer rural demand.
The private car segment grew by 1.1% and
the commercial vement vehicle segment
had a degrowth of 3.8% for quarter 4
financial year 2025
as reported by far which had an impact
on motor insurance growth for quarter 4
financial year 2025. However, for the
coming year the auto industry is
expected to have mid singledigit growth.
We remain positive for the motor
insurance business with increasing
penetration in the old vehicle segments.
The health segment continues to be one
of the fastest growing segments and is
the largest contributor to the industry
constituting 38.1% of the GDP mix for
financial year 2025. However, the
industry growth in financial year 2025
was impacted due to the one by
accounting norm and lower growth in the
health segment, health benefit segment
attributable to lower dispersement by of
credit by NBFC's and MFIs. We believe
that the increasing demand for health
protection coupled with increased
medical inflation may drive double-digit
growth in the health segment in the
coming year. Here were some key economic
changes which were announced during
quarter 4 financial year 2025.
The budgetary announcement of income tax
relief provided is expected to result in
an additional 1 trillion in the hands of
Indian taxpaying population thereby
leading to a high disposable income. The
second consecutive interest rate cutting
of norms applicable to NBFC lending
coupled with infusion of liquidity by
RBI should also support credit growth.
These policy changes aim to encourage
spending and investment. They are also
expected to stimulate demand for goods
and services thereby boosting
consumption and preparing demand for
risk protection through insurance
solutions.
However, we remain vigilant on the
ongoing geopolitical developments which
may pose risk to both global growth and
the Indian economy.
Now, let me give you a brief give you an
update on the regulatory developments.
The regulatory the authority during
financial year 2025 continued with
various reforms seeking to expand the
market and increase the penetration of
insurance product towards the mission of
insurance for all by 2047.
I would like to mention key circulars
which were introduced in quarter 4 2025
regarding capping the increase in senior
citizens health insurance premium rates
to 10% peranom and introduction of BIMA
ESBA facility for health insurance
policies. We believe these regulatory
changes will improve affordability and
create operational ease for policy
holders.
Overall, we remain positive that the GI
industry is poised to grow in the medium
to long term given the favorable
economic and regulatory environment, low
penetration and relatively higher
disposable income.
Now coming to the industry performance
for quarter 4 and financial year 2025.
The gross direct premium income grew by
1.7% and 6.2% for quarter 4 2025 and
financial year 2025 respectively.
Excluding the impact of the 1 byN
accounting norm, the GDPI grew by 8.6%
for financial year 2025.
Excluding crop and mass health, the GDPI
grew by 4.9% and 8% for quarter 4 2025
and financial year 2025 respectively.
Peing on the specific segments within
the industry, the commercial segment
reported a marginal degrowth of 1.2% 2%
and growth of 1.5% for quarter 4 and
financial year 2025. Within this, the
fire segment registered a degrowth of
1.8% and 5.3% for quarter 4 financial
year 2025 and financial year 2025
respectively on account of pricing
pressure excluding the fire segment. The
over overall commercial segment grew by
8 and a half% for financial year 2025.
The motor segment grew by 6.9% for
quarter 4 of financial year 2025 and 8%
for financial year 2025. The growth in
the segment has been lower due to muted
vehicle sales and continued pricing
pressures reflected by high industry
combined ratio.
The health se the health segment grew at
3.7% and 9% for quarter 4 2025 and
financial year 2025. Within this group
health grew at 4.5% and 10.6% for
quarter 4 2025 and financial year 2025
respectively and retail health grew at
7.6% and 12.1% in quarter 4 2025 and
financial year 2025 respectively.
Looking at the underlying performance of
the industry, you may recall our
discussion a year back during our
earnings call where we expect we where
we expected some semblance in
underwriting discipline in the market
due to improvement in the industry's
combined ratio during that period.
However, the combined ratio for the
industry has actually worsened to 113.2%
for 9 month as against 112.2% 2% for 9
month financial year 2024. The combined
ratio for the private sector has
worsened to triple 1.21% for 9 month
2025 from 108.3% for 9 month financial
year 2024. The industry worsening was
largely due to motor segment combined
ratio which increased to 123.8%
in 9 month financial year 2025 as
against 118.2%
in 9 month financial year 2024. Our
continued focus on driving profitable
growth helped us to improve our combined
ratio from 103.7%
in 9 month financial year 2024 to 102.8%
in 9 months financial year 2025 and
103.3%
in full financial year 2024 to 102.6%
in financial for the financial year 2025
on N basis.
I will now walk you through the company
performance across key business segments
during quarter 4 and financial year
2025.
The company's GDPR registered a growth
of 8% for quarter 4 2025 and 11% for
financial year 2025 on N basis with the
1 byN accounting norm for quarter 4 2025
the company registered a growth of 2.3%
is as against the industry growth of
1.7%
and for financial year 2025 the company
registered a growth of 8.3% as against
the industry growth of 6.2% 2% excluding
crop and mass health. The company's
growth was 2.2% and 7.7%
compared to the industry growth of 4.9%
and 8% for quarter 4 2025 and financial
year 2025 respectively.
In the commercial line segment in
quarter 4 2025 our growth was at 2.8% is
against the industry growth of 1.2%.
For financial year 2025, we grew by 2.5
2.1%
as against the industry growth of 1 and
a half%. Thereby maintaining market
share. This indicates the strength of a
brand relationship and service quality
in an environment where industry face
continued pricing pressure throughout
the year. In the fire segment, we grew
in line with the industry and in marine
cargo engineering and liability lines of
business. We reported growth higher than
the industry leading to market share
accretion.
In motor segment we grew at.1% for
quarter 4 2025 as against the industry
growth of 6.9%.
We continue to drive our motor strategy
based on granular portfolio segmentation
and food and risk selection. For the
financial year 2025 we grew by 11 and a
half% as again the industry growth of
8%. Consequently our market share grew
to 10.8% 8% for financial year 2025
versus 10.5% for financial year 2024.
The portfolio mix for private car, two
wheeler and CV stood at 53.4%,
25.4%
and 21.2% respectively. Our continued
focus on multi- channelannel
distribution, underwriting capabilities
and efficient claim settlement and
actual practices helped us in
maintaining a leadership position.
Moving to the health segment, we grew by
22.1%
and 19.2% for quarter 4 financial year
2025 and financial year 2025
respectively. With the one byan
accounting norm, we drew by 9.7% and
12.6% for quarter 4 2025 and financial
year 2025 respectively.
Our retail health segment registered a
growth at 47.7% for quarter 4 financial
year 2025 with the 1 byN accounting
norm. The growth of quarter 4 2025
was 25.1% as against the industry growth
of 7.6%.
For financial year 2025 the overall
growth stood at 38.1%.
With one by an accounting norm, the
growth for financial year 2025 was 25%.
As again the industry growth of 12.1%.
As a result, we gained market share from
3% in financial year 2024 to 3.3% for
financial year 2025.
The group health employed employee
segment witnessed growth of 24.9% and
18.5% for quarter 4 2025 and financial
year 2025
respectively. A group other business deg
the degrowth was 30% for quarter 4 2025.
For financial year 2025, group other
business had a muted growth of 5.3% on
account of impact on health benefit
business through the banker channel with
the one by accounting norms. This
segment showed a degrowth of 10.5% for
the year.
We had spoken about various one team
initiatives in earlier earnings call.
One of the initiatives we had spoken
about was the consolidation of customerf
facing digital assets like I take care
help apps and digital alliances under
one digital to deliver a superior
customer experience and to drive
efficiencies. Some of the digital
outcomes achieved in financial year 2025
include increasing unique customer visit
by 2x on our digital platform. 37%
growth in fresh transactions on our
digital platform. Downloads for our
one-stop solution one take your apps
surpassed surpassed 14.9 million.
The business done through the app stood
at 927.7
million and 2653.2 2 million for quarter
4, financial year 2025 and financial
year 2025 respectively. Consequently,
our customerf facing digital asset
business grew by 15.8%
constituting 6.6% of our overall GDP for
financial year 2025.
Now I would like to share with you some
initiatives taken by us for improving
the customer experience and driving
efficiencies for claims
on the motor side. A preferred partner
network serviced 74.1%
of our nonEM claims in quarter 4 2025 up
from 69.6% in quarter 4 2024. For
financial year 2025 this number stood at
73.2%
up from 65% in financial year 2024.
Our cloud calling facilities were used
by 89.6% 6% of our motor customers in
quarter 4 financial year 2025 as against
77% in quarter 4 2024. For the full year
this number was at 86% as against 49%
previous year. This resulted in the
reduction of cost to claim ratio by 21%
for the year.
Our
average claim settlement period for
retail lines of business has seen
improvement from 6 days in financial
year 2024 to 5 days in financial year
for motor ODI and for motor and for five
and from 5 days in financial year 2024
to 3 days in financial year 2025 for
health. Our ISI initiative which was
launched in April 2024 offered an
onground claim support to over 90,000
customers across 56 cities and 2,500
hospital network in financial year 2025.
A focus on customer experience and
process efficiencies has led to healthy
NPS of 67 and 69 for health and motor
claims respectively for 9 months 2025.
With all the above efforts, we are
pleased to share that the company's
premium growth has been higher by 210
basis points as against the industry
growth. Our focus on driving profitable
opportunities has further resulted in
improvement in the combined ratio from
103.3%
in financial year 2024 to 102.6% in
financial year 2025 on N basis. on on
the 1 byN accounting norm the combined
ratio stood at 102.8%
leading to a pad growth of 30.7%
and then delivering ROE for the year at
19.1%.
As we enter into the new financial year,
we remain committed to achieving the
desired scale through creation of
positive customer experiences,
leveraging data analytics and a
technology first approach, harnessing a
multi-product multi-distribution
strategy and with a continued focus on
product innovation
with a core philosophy of one team, we
continue to scale up the profit pools
and to drive sustainable growth.
I will now request Gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
recently concluded quarter and financial
year. Thanks Ajivie and uh good evening
to each one of you. I will now give you
a brief overview of the financial
performance for the recently concluded
quarter and the financial year. We have
uploaded the results presentation on our
website. You can access it as we walk
you through the performance numbers.
With effect from October 1, 2024,
long-term products are accounted on a 1
byN basis as mandated by the regulator.
Hence, Q4 and FI25 numbers are not
comparable with prior periods. For more
details on the impact, refer to slide
number 15 of our investor presentation
for further details. The gross direct
premium income of the company was at
rupes 268.33 billion in FI25 as against
rupees 247.76 billion in FI24. a growth
of 8.3% as against industry growth of
6.2%.
GDP of the company was at 62.11 billion
in Q4 FI25 as against 60.73 billion in
Q4 FI24. A growth of 2.3% as against
industry growth of 1.7%.
On the retail side of the business, GDP
of the motor segment was at 107.4
billion in FI25 as against 96.34 billion
in FI24, registering a growth of 11.5%.
The advanced premium for the motor
segment was at rupes 37.17 billion at
March 31 2025 as against 36.44 billion
as at December 31 2024. GDP of the L
segment was at rupes 69.5 billion in
FI25 as against 61.71 billion in FI24
registering a growth of 12.6%. Our
agents which includes the point of sale
distribution count was at 1 lak 40,736
as at March 31 2025 up from 1 lakh 40,77
as at December 31 2024. GDP of our
commercial line segment was at 69.95
billion in FI25 as against 68.51 billion
in FI24 registering a growth of 2.1% as
against industry growth of 1.5%.
Resultedly our combined ratio stood at
102.8%. 8% for FI25 as against 103.3%
for FI24 excluding the impact of CAT
losses of 94 billion in FI25 and 1.37
billion in FI24. The combined ratio was
102.4% and 102.5% respectively. Combined
ratio for quarter 4 FI25 was 102.5% as
against 102.3% in quarter 4 FI24.
Our investment assets during the quarter
rose to rupes 535.0 08 billion as at
March 31, 2025, up from rupees 515.99 97
billion as at December 31, 2024. Our
investment leverage net of borrowing was
3.74 times as at March 31, 2025 as
against 3.76 times at December 31, 2024.
Investment income was at 42.5 billion in
FI25 as against 36.1 billion in FI24. On
a quarterly basis, investment income was
at 8.77 billion in Q4 FI25 as against
9.54 billion in Q4 FI24.
Our capital gains net of impairment on
investment assets stood at rupees 8.02
billion for the full year as compared to
5.51 billion in the previous financial
year. Capital gains net of impairment on
investment assets stood at rupees.06 06
billion in quarter 4 FI25 as compared to
rups 1.56 billion in quarter 4 fi24.
Our profit before tax grew by 30% at
33.21 billion in FI25 as against 25.55
billion in FI24. Whereas PBT grew by
4.2% at 6.68 billion in quarter 4 FI25
as against 6.98 billion rupees in
quarter 4 FI24. Consequently, profit
after tax grew by 30.7% at 25.08 billion
in FI25 as against 19.19 billion in
FI24. PAD regrrew by 1.9% to rupees 5.1
billion in Q4 FI25 as against 5.19
billion in quarter 4 FI24. The board of
directors of the company has proposed a
final dividend of rupees 7 per share per
FI25. This statement is however subject
to approval of shareholders in the
ensuing annual general meeting of the
company. The overall dividend for FI25
including the proposed final dividend is
rupees 12.5 per share. Last year the
overall dividend was rupees 11 per
share. Return on average equity was
19.1% in FI25 as against 17.2% in FI24.
Return on equity for quarter 4 this year
was 14.5 as against 17.8 in quarter 4 of
last year. Solveny ratio was at 2.69
times at March 31 2025 as against 2.36
times at December 31 2024 continued to
be higher than the regulatory minimum
requirement of 1.5. As I conclude, I
would like to assert that we remain
focused on our strategy of driving
profitable growth, consistent and
sustainable value creation for all our
stakeholders while ensuring that the
interest of policy holders is in the
forefront at all times. I'd like to
thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we will be happy to
take any questions that you may have.
Thank you.
Thank you. We will now begin the
question and answer session. Anyone who
wishes to ask a question may press star
and one on your touchstone telephone. If
you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue, you may press star and
two. Participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question. Ladies
and gentlemen will wait for a moment
while the question queue assembles.
The first question comes on the line of
Pra Jane from Mutal Oswal Financial
Services Limited. Please go ahead.
Yeah. Hi. Uh a good set of numbers on
especially on the combined ratio front.
Uh just your thoughts on uh know how do
we see the growth from here. uh firstly
no from a overall GWP perspective uh
given the one by impact would continue
uh to be there in one match of mix one
of FI26 and second half would see
unwinding of uh the GWP uh and
contributing to some part of growth. So
that would be uh the first question. Uh
second question would be on your
combined ratio or whether you would look
at combined ratio or further improving
from the one that reported uh in in the
for FI25
and uh on the fire segment if you could
highlight you know what are the kind of
renewals we've seen in January and uh
also in the uh in the April renewals and
those three questions. Thanks. Okay.
Yeah. Thanks Br. I think uh with respect
to the growth uh even when I was reading
in terms of uh what it is line by line I
had covered but again I'll I'll talk
about it uh motor per se we are
expecting on the new sale mid single
digit. We also going by the numbers as
has been put across by other OEMs as to
what they are seeing. Albeit the base on
the private car in particular is high.
Uh I also spoke about the fact that the
quarter 4 two-heer numbers were they're
negative which was a bit of a surprise
as well as what we saw in quarter three
and commercial vehicle I would be more
positive overall because government
capex and lot of other activities which
in the last financial year had remained
subdued should get picked up. So net net
motor we will see single digit to maybe
at just about double digit growth is
what our prediction is and look all of
these things can change real time we'll
keep you updated but that's what our
belief is on the health side pre our own
belief is we will should see double
digit growth uh now health is two
components retail health and as well as
the group health part of it I'm more
clearly talking about the retail health
path which will continue to see far more
uh incremental business in terms of new
to insurance and also there would be
whatever interest growth that comes out
in terms of overall this. So we would
remain positive on help and help with a
38% contribution will not be surprised
if we see that contribution probably
going to a 40% and thereabouts and
becomes the largest and will continue to
be the largest player. The last but uh
not the least in terms of the commercial
line of business uh we've had a very one
of the most difficult years on
commercial line if you see uh you've
never seen a growth of this nature going
to you know single digit in last 7 to 8
years
clearly it had multiple factors fire
pricing which we spoke about it however
going forward as the and you spoke about
and I'll probably talk about the other
question that you put across we saw a
lot of semblance in the industry overall
on the fire side
and on that basis we do believe and we
do see relatively much better numbers on
fire and with the activity of the capex
which is coming through engineering line
of business should also do well. So
overall commercial we would like to
believe that there should be a there
should be back to a double digit kind of
a growth at the industry level. I think
your last question was on the combine on
the combine. Right. So I think P again
if you look at what we have been saying
is uh obviously our performance will
will be in the context of how the market
uh performs. So which is why we kind of
also put that out as a part of the
opening transcript as in to say that at
the beginning of the financial year
concluded we had kind of possibly
expected a lot more semblance to pay out
but in reality if you look at I think
the market seems to have gone slightly
more in that sense north. I think
combined ratios have kind of increased
by almost about 100 basis point at an
aggregate level. So obviously we'll wait
for the fullear numbers to play out in
terms of what the players report but
obviously we will be at it when it comes
to let's say driving profitable
opportunities. So hence the endeavor
will be obviously to try and see how we
can create lot more efficiencies whether
it is on loss ratios cost etc etc and
obviously reselect the right portfolio
mix but obviously we will see how the
market direction plays out and in that
context is how we would also want to see
our combined play through but having
said that definitely I think the gap
between us and the industry combined
whichever way you look at it I think
obviously we will be able to kind of do
lot more uh positives to play out and in
the aggregate I think what we have
spoken about is time and again we will
look for trying to see if we can do that
improvement in the return on equity that
we can give to stakeholders uh the range
that we have generally spoken about in
that range of 16 to 18% the endeavor
will be to obviously try and see over
the long term to move towards the 18 to
20 depending on how the market plays out
yeah so I think and also the simple
answer is uh would we like to improve
our combine uh certainly yes uh and as
Gopal mentioned uh we saw a trajectory
when we came in last year where industry
combine had shown an improvement on the
basis of that we felt we will go uh we
also would like to see a similar thing
but the deterioration has happened and
the deteration more has happened in
terms of motor moving from 118 to 123
for a 9 month combined but so that being
said we will let uh these things play
out uh and in our mind the single factor
that drives is are we able to generate
the roe and that's what largely Gopal is
speaking about it uh as far as we as a
you know uh as an entity is concerned.
All right. Just your thought on TV price
that will be my last.
So we always remain hopeful but uh no
news as yet. So uh is the industry
seeking it? Answer is yes. Is it come
through? The answer is no.
So we are planning
in that sense. Yeah. Yeah.
Okay. Yeah. Thank you so much. Thanks.
Thank you. A reminder to all the
participants in the interest of time
please restrict questions to two per
participants. Next question comes from
the line of Sankit Koda with Aendaspar.
Please go ahead.
Yeah, thank you for the opportunity.
Gopal in the current quarter we seems to
have done little more reinsurance
accepted business because there is a
meaningful difference between GDPI and
GWP in the quarter almost 10%age. So I
just wanted to understand the color of
this business and um do you see uh
opportunity in range accepted with price
hikes going up probably you will do the
same kind of a business in in subsequent
year also uh any any thoughts on those
lines just just want to understand and
and the second question uh Gupal was
that uh uh you see see if you if you
could not book capital gains in the
current quarter uh your your yield
remained at 6.3 suppose hypothetically
market remains weak largely for FI26.
So, so is it fair to say that your 6.3
6.4 is the yield for for uh for for for
probably for the entire FI26 and
therefore we need to look ro from from
that perspective. Uh just wanted to
understand that a bit from you and
lastly data keeping question if you can
give retail health loss ratio breakup
and motor GWP break up into new and old
which you usually do. Thank you. Yeah,
maybe I think I'll first uh do the data
keeping question first. Uh which is
something that keeps coming to us every
quarter. Uh so I'm just kind of giving
you the numbers both for Q4 of last year
and Q4 of this year first and then I
will give the numbers for the full year
in terms of the breakup between
corporate health and uh the retail
indemnity numbers. Uh so quarter 4 of
last year corporate health uh loss
ratios were 88.1%.
And the retail indemnity numbers again
for quarter four of last year was 64.6%.
Vizly this quarter 4 of this year
corporate health is at 97.2%.
And retail health broadly the range that
we have spoken about is at about 64.8%.
On a full year basis this number for
corporate health stands at about 93.7
last year and the current year re I mean
again last year retail indemnity numbers
is 65.4. 4 year this number for
corporate health is at 97.6
and retail indemnity is 67.9.
So that's the numbers in terms of the
break up between corporate health and
retail health. Now coming to your point
first question on reinsurance accepted
uh one at an aggregate level obviously
if you ask us underwriting philosophy is
to drive profitable growth whether it is
with respect to the gross direct premium
income that we write or even with
respect to let's say the reinsurances
acceptances to the extent whatever we do
so therefore from a philosophy
standpoint one thing we will stand
committed to driving profitable growth
across the revenue streams that we
source having said that I think if you
look at at an agree ate level I think in
terms of the roughly the premium that we
would have written of close to about
28,000 crores or thereabout the extent
of reinsurance inward will be a
single-digit number um so hence to that
extent I think a large part of the
opportunities is what we see clearly
even in the domestic market plus at the
same time obviously we look for given
the fact that we also have an office in
our IO uh business uh we would want to
kind of continue to see how we can
leverage profitable opportunities even
through the IIO business. So that is how
we would kind of play through whether a
particular business comes through in a
quarter or otherwise. I think again as I
keep saying our business is
significantly cyclical and wherever we
see opportunities play out is how you
will continue to see the mix of business
between direct RAI etc etc play out. the
larger number to look at will be more on
an annual basis that will be more
reflective of where we are in terms of
our approach to writing domestic and
reinsurance in good. So your second
point on uh yeah sorry good point. So so
I was asking this question predominantly
because because you you will see a
better pricing environment in next
fiscal year. So so if other segments
slow down say motor slows down a bit
because of the weak auto cycle. Uh is it
fair to say that this product might be
an opportunity
uh approach to to uh to to drive the
overall growth maybe from that pricing
environment.
Exactly. circuit your point is
absolutely right that's exactly what I
said I think if you ask us for us both
of them are preferred areas of
opportunity so therefore to that extent
where we see uh preferable segments for
us to be able to underwrite we will look
at both will it suddenly become a very
large proportion of our overall revenue
streams at this point of time clearly
not but obviously we will look at uh the
as I said profitable opportunities
between domestic and the reinsurance
inward and the revenues that we'll
eventually source will be mix of
uh on your point on capital gains, I
think uh if you look at u the uh
approach that we have taken in so far as
uh building the investment portfolio is
concerned, I think uh the treasury team
has done a brilliant job uh in terms of
how to kind of balance the mix of asset
classes between equity and the fixed
income portfolio and that's the reason
during this last periods of high
interest rate regime we have been able
to kind of significantly go long and
which That is the reason I think even in
our earlier earlier earnings call we
have spoken about of our duration of the
book that still continues to be slightly
in excess of uh 5.3 years and if you
look at the yield to maturity uh the
yield to maturity of the book also
currently stands at about 7.55%.
And hence uh and which is what is kind
of translating into if you look at our
marktomarket positions on the overall
investment book while on the roughly an
aggregate marktomarket gain as on the
balance sheet date of roughly about 1800
uh 18 billion um in terms of the
marktomarket unrealized gains is what we
have. So I think the portfolio is well
positioned. The question to ask for is
what happens in case if you see possibly
sustained periods of price competition
or sustained periods of low interest
rate regime. Now all of that I think in
so in in so far as the second part of
let's say periods of low interest rate
sustaining in the next year I think to
that extent I think our duration call
will kind of largely reflect that and of
course incre reinvestment of the
incremental cash flows will get
subjected to getting placed at a lower
interest rate and that will be true for
the entire market. So therefore the
entire market will have to work much
more harder in terms of improving the
pricing and therefore on balance which
is what we keep saying I think the roe
range that we will work which will be
through a combination of driving
underwriting outcomes and return on
investment that will be in the range of
18 to 20%. assuming the market obviously
shows signs of change and also you know
sake now I'll just uh give you the uh
you know lay of the land uh if you go
back in time in April uh as we were
finishing our financial year 2024
if you would have told us to guess the
growth rate for commercial line of
business we would have said definitely
it will be in double digits uh if you
would have told us on the banker line of
business which is a big practice we have
again we would have said a decent with
double digit but as transpired in the
course of the year both of these lines
that are relatively difficult here but
again the emphasis that we have as a
multi-line multi- product companies are
we agile enough to toggle uh even you
look at the numbers that you see quarter
and quarter in motor we had a
significant gain in quarter 1 and
quarter two and again in quarter three
and quarter four
we have the PSUs which have built up
severe intensity which is not making
much of an economic sense
and you have seen us growing relatively
low while we have finished the year
overall with a gain on market share. So
what I'm trying to emphasize to all of
you is uh what we see and what comes
through there can be a gap and as an
organization we are expected to maintain
that level of agility to make shifts
happen and what we predict not
necessarily the way the market will end
up behaving. So we will have to factor
that and then I come back in light of
that the focus intently for us as an
organization boils down to are we able
to generate the you know uh that is
expected by all our stakeholders.
All right. Yeah.
Please rejoin the queue for mr.
Please rejoin the queue for more
questions.
Thank you.
Next question comes from the line of
Nitesh Jen with Invest. Please go ahead.
Uh thanks thanks for the opportunity.
Two question. First is on fire pricing.
Are we already seeing signs of
improvement in fire pricing for the
industry?
Yeah, the answer is yes. there is uh uh
some semblance uh but I would like to
put a word of caution because uh we
still have to see a lot more flowing
through but as things stand in uh first
couple of weeks of April there was uh
definitely much better discipline in the
market.
Sure. Uh secondly, can you speak about
IFRS impact on uh our uh profitability
or ROE any any rough indication because
some of the other companies are are
disclosing their IFRS number uh which is
also quite useful. So if we can also
give some some indication around that.
So so Gopal will give the indication. My
my only point is you know just to put
things in perspective uh there is an
economic value there is an accounting
value. All these nuance changes are
eventually
on the accounting part of it. There is
obviously an implication in terms of how
positively IFRS can help us but we as an
organization would 100% commit ourselves
on the economic value. Not only Gopar if
you can just talk about this spoken we
have actually kind of spoken this even
in past calls. So therefore I think our
stance would still be the same as in to
say that uh I think we will continue to
evaluate businesses more on an economic
basis because end of the day that's what
will eventually translate in terms of
what is the outcome that we are writing
from a risk perspective. U transitions
to IFRS obviously are accounting changes
which we obviously we will be uh in that
sense well prepared and at this point of
time obviously we are getting most of
our work done internally whether it is
in terms of understanding the impact of
change getting systems geared up so that
as and when there is a clear regulatory
stipulations as what they have currently
indicated. So we will be kind of pretty
much ready with whatever it takes to do
the transition. But at the same time I
think what I I think we have been
speaking about also is the fact that as
and when we will eventually transition
to IFRS there will be a lot of in that
sense uh assumptions uh which will have
to be made by market at large. I think
it is important for again various
stakeholders to ensure consistency in
comparison a need for possibly to see if
we can get a lot more alignment with
some of those assumptions that the
market participants use. So I think our
endeavor is in that direction and which
is what we are working with the council
to see how we can possibly play that
role uh far better at this in the
current times. But obviously internally
we are pretty much well prepared. Uh
major areas of impact I think I already
called out. So in that sense no specific
incremental areas to call out as a part
of the current uh impact assessment uh
that we have done but yes we are we are
ready and we will roll out whenever we
see the uh regulatory timelines coming
into action.
Okay. And then uh when we speak about
economic perspective we are talking more
about ROE and not combined ratio right?
Yeah, because end of the day I think
whatever you write has to kind of
translate into a return to stakeholders
through a combination of what we deliver
on underwriting plus obviously how
effectively are we able to put the cash
flows to use. So hence to that extent is
what we will kind of be largely driving
as institution.
Thank you sir. Thank you. That's it from
my side. Thanks. Thanks.
Thank you.
Next question comes from the line of
Ainash Singh with MK Global Financial
Services Limited. Please go ahead.
Yeah. Hi. Uh good evening. Thank for the
opportunity. Just uh couple of
questions. First one is on uh you know
motor TP. Uh if I see again uh around
915 or of reserve releases you had this
fiscal. Now of course still you have not
touched your FY23 onwards if I see or
yeah now uh the backdrop is that the
price hike is not happening. uh do you
see I mean uh the support from reserve
releases to continue to provide you know
the support uh uh in terms of a motor TV
claims ratio to catch up with you know
the uh claims in place and then on that
front also another question related is
that okay industry has seen a kind of a
despite this um coming the overall
non-clims expense going up now do you
see that scope next year if the claims
were to be under pressure opex side
because now the March 26 deadline for
EUM limits reaching some kind of a you
know uh sanity prevailing among the some
extreme or aggressive peers would you
would that lead to your opex further
improving from here because at the end
of the day that's a sort of a relative
market relative phenomena you cannot
outpric yourself in the market so if if
the peers were to improve will that also
be kind of a you know helpful and the
second one on the app on renewal if I
read correctly India even in Asia the
resource capacities uh and pricing both
have been kind of a favorable. So in
back in that backdrop does that sort of
a help in terms of your profitability in
these kind of a reinflance heavy line
item like commercialized. Thanks. Okay.
So maybe I will take the second part
first. I think what you observed is
absolutely right. Uh so so hence
obviously that aids us uh which is what
we have been kind of talking through. uh
I think the more the market gets
sensible in so far as the need for
compliance to the expense of management
guidelines are concerned that kind of
definitely augers well from an overall
market discipline standpoint. So and
therefore and again as you rightly
indicated FI26 is a time period that the
regulator has stipulated within which
companies are expected to tow the line
when it comes to meeting the guidelines
on expense of management. So, so
obviously this is something that uh we
would be definitely kind of closely
watching for but at the same time I'm
sure all of you are also kind of clearly
hearing that even the regulator is
wanting to make sure that as an industry
pretty much everyone in the market kind
of follows the discipline on compliance
to expense of management. So hence uh uh
the short answer is of course it augers
well in so far as uh favorable market
development is concerned and within that
indeed obviously that's something that
we have always seen when the market gets
far more sensible on underwriting then
ISIS by virtue of its uh brand
technology service etc etc is obviously
able to kind of command an incremental
market growth uh without compromising on
underwriting outcome. So that's the
response to the second one to the
response on the third one. I think with
respect to the reinsurance uh renewal
cycle again ain I think you all
understand insurance as much as what we
do. Uh so therefore uh so therefore in
that sense uh uh the the renewals are
always through cycles. You will always
see periods of softness and at some
points of time the market starts to get
hardened. uh I think the key is end of
the day I think if you look at from our
standpoint what we have again
particularly in the commercial lines
where you relatively see higher
proportion of reinsurance we have
continued to stay disciplined on picking
risks which we think are viable from an
under from a underwriting perspective uh
depend irrespective of which cycle the
market is currently operating at in
terms of uh the reinsurance renewals.
Now that's what is finding favor if you
were to see which is what put out also
on our investor presentation as in to
say that the quality of the partners
with whom we work clearly is kind of
pretty much there. So obviously we don't
in that sense want to take any
unnecessary credit risk. So we are very
very conscious of making sure that we
work with highquality panel of
reinsurers. So that gives us a lot of
comfort when it comes to getting
capacity and also now to your point on
terms obviously it's again we get start
we get terms which are better than the
market so even this year at least what
we understand relative to the market I
think we have been given the
underwriting performance that we have
exhibited to the reinsurers I think we
believe we have been able to get terms
both on commissions and the cost that we
incur for protecting our net uh to be
possibly better than where the market is
placed at and that will again kind of
aid us in our ability to further uh
dwell on incremental market share. So
that's in response to the third question
on reinsurance renewal cycle. To your
first point on motor third party I think
again I keep saying this u I think the
ranges is what we have spoken about in
terms of the motor loss ratio. Again I
will keep saying we have to look at
motor as in the aggregate and the range
that we have spoken about even in the
earlier earnings call uh for the segment
has been between 65 to 67 broadly if you
look at the loss ratio outcome that has
played out for even the current year is
pretty much within the range that we
have been kind of talking about. So
hence that's how we look at now what can
happen in case if no third party price
increase sustains for one more year in
FI26. Obviously that means we'll have to
do a lot more work to make sure that we
are able to identify better risk
selection and continue to see how we can
drive profitable growth. That's what we
will focus on and more importantly let's
say for the market they will have to
work much more harder particularly for
those companies which have combined with
no third party price increase and a
compliance to expense of management yes
is something that some of those market
participants will have to work on. So
again we believe we're getting favorably
placed in terms of the opportunity that
one sees on uh motor third party and
finally on the point on reserving I
think again our approach to the acturial
principles pretty much stands intact
there is absolutely no change in the way
how we have been kind of reserving for
the portfolio in terms of consistency
and that's the reason even if you would
have seen the reserve redundancy that
you would have seen across key lines we
continue to see one more year of reserve
redundancy. So that reflects the quality
of reserving that we have been able to
kind of play up to. So hence no change
in the actial thought process.
Thank you. Very clear. Thanks. Thank
you.
Thank you. Next question comes from the
line of Shria Shivani with CLSA. Please
go ahead. Hi, thank you for the
opportunity. I have one question that is
on the expense ratio for the quarter. Um
so the way I understood uh the the
impact of the 1 byN accounting last time
uh the quarters are similar in terms of
what happened in 3Q to 4Q in terms of
the volume growth that you got or uh how
much you have retained then ideally your
expense ratio should have been similar
to what it was in 3Q even the absolute
amount has declined in 4Q uh if I if I
don't talk about the ratio even the
absolute amount has declined. So what
has helped us in having much lesser net
commissions at least if if you can help
me understand this is just about the
quarter
again it's like it's like the question
that keeps coming to us in terms of the
third party loss experience on how the
loss ratio movement are happening
between quarters uh I think again I will
kind of keep reiterating I think our our
focus is very clearly is to make sure
that expense plus commissions put
together as a company we are very very
conscious of making sure that we run the
overall operations at a EOM threshold
which is less than 30% and which is what
if you see on a full year basis I think
for us the expense of management number
stands at about 29.5%.
uh so hence I think we're pretty much uh
committed within a quarter various
factors in terms of business mix in
terms of efficiencies that we always
keep looking for in terms of our own
internal processes
and so there are numerous factors that
go into it. So hence which is why we
keep urging to keep looking at numbers
more on an annual basis rather than a
particular quarter and more so on an
absolute basis I think again there can
be many factors to it. So for example I
mean whenever if there are periods where
I do a lot more of those investments in
that quarter you will see the cost
hitting us uh and and so on. So a better
number to look at will be more the
expense of management number than
anything else. No and also share I mean
since you're and you're comparing
quarter three and quarter four just to
highlight it's the configuration of
business that comes in in quarter three
we have far more new book that comes in
it's a season where you know the sale of
new goes our market share motor also
grows in a very very significant way in
January typical Jan also is a reasonably
big line on the commercial side of the
business which can further impact the
expense ratio in a positive manner so
it's more driven by configuration know
what nature of business you write which
creates that differentiation
then that's about and you know that when
these things happen and you have a
quarter where there's a new coming in it
would impact uh us uh in a far more you
know yeah okay yeah the only thing I was
getting confused that if the retention
ratios are similar between 3Q and 4Q
then your commission rates should have
been similar ideally your net commission
uh ratios but I get the part that if
you've written more commercial line in
4Q then obviously Yeah. Okay. Okay.
Fair. Okay. Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. Next question comes from the
line of Praar Sharma with Jeff. Please
go ahead.
Hi, good evening. uh just wanted to
delve upon Steve's comment on you know
the uh pricing stance by some of the
PSUs or broader market in the uh motor
vehicle business. uh could you just
elaborate on this that uh you know from
what segments of uh general uh GI
operators did you see some bit of an
aggressive stance uh and uh has there
been any change because you know while
we talk about the EOM uh sunset for FI26
uh are the private ones also genuinely
trying to consolidate on pricing and
second connected to this is uh is there
a possibility or is there a discussion
around the EOM getting pushed out by a
year or so just so that everybody makes
it without too much disruption. Thank
you. Uh so I think uh on the PSU
aggression uh it's primarily driven very
extensively on the motor side. Uh
village sustained too early to comment.
There were shades of that visible in
quarter 3 but quarter four if you see
they have overall buckled the trend and
they have gained significant market
share also in the uh motor segment. Uh
it would be anybody's guess in terms of
what their plan is. Uh we are pretty
ready to face whatever be the you know
trajectory that they have and uh we'll
wait and see how it pans out. uh we
would continue to as I said in my uh you
know in my you know initial remarks that
we would continue to flop prudency
because these things can happen at multi
multiple level uh at with multiple
players sometimes it's private sector
sometimes it's public sector but we need
to stick to our trajectory of what we
want to do uh with respect to expense of
management uh deferment uh our
understanding is that uh what has got
called out was Poland final. Uh we do
believe it will be it will be good in
long term for the industry if there's a
seminars on that count. Uh we have no
one to comment in terms of whether a
dispensation will be given for another
year. But if you ask a personal belief
another year of dispensation will make
them continue with the practice as it
exists and will not change anything
because then they can ask another year
of dispensation.
uh that's where we would be you know uh
that's where we would leave this part of
the conversation at least.
Perfect. Thank you so much. Yeah. Thank
you.
Thank you. Next question comes from the
line of Aditi Johi with JB Morgan.
Please go ahead.
Uh yes uh thank you for taking my
question. Uh just a very simple one.
Sorry could not uh go through the
presentation. With respect to the
investment income was it uh uh in the
fourth quarter it was uh lower on an
year-on-year basis. I just wanted to
understand is it majorly on account of
interest income or on account of lower
uh realized gains. Yeah, we put that as
a part of the opening script. So largely
it's because of uh I mean the nature of
how we kind of real the nature of how we
run the overall investment book. Uh the
short answer is capital gains. Quarter 4
last year capital gains was roughly
about 150 crores plus this year pretty
much our capital gains is as good as a
very very small number of roughly about
6 crores. So that's last that's the
reason why you see uh the overall uh
investment income for Q4 of this year to
be slightly lower than the Q4 of last
year. But having said that I think what
has worked well again as I said I think
the treasury team has done a great job
in trying to make sure that the
portfolio has got significantly kind of
balanced to make sure that we go long
and hence uh which is why again time and
again we have been giving the yield to
maturity numbers which used to be less
than 7% that number as we speak
currently stands at about 7.55%. So, so
this is for here for here to stay and
hence uh at least for quarter 4 the
short answer is capital gains. Yeah. And
also you know uh something which I must
put across what our treasury team has
done is even over quarter and quarter we
have increased the yield of the book
from 7% to 7.55.
So which is a big one with the tenor
also which has gone to 5.34.
uh overall it puts us well in terms of
the current scenario that exists on the
that exist on the you know interest rate
part
and also quarter three it was more of a
tactical call where our investment team
felt that it was much better to book
capital gains in that quarter versus
what would happen in quarter 4 uh in
hindsight it did work out for us
okay that's here. Thank you. Thanks.
Thank you. Thank you. Next question
comes from the line of Naji
with UPS securityities. Please go ahead.
Yeah. Hi. Uh so uh my question is
regarding getting to 526. How often
think about the group given you know
what we have discussed? uh there still
remain out on certainities as you
mentioned and the preview could be
different than what we right now you
know think about as sorry to stop you we
not able to hear you you're not that
audible uh is it better now
yeah maybe if you can just repeat your
question n that will help us so so one
question is on the on the growth side uh
because given this end will kind of
normalize from October
uh how does one think about overall
growth and uh the pepper areas will
remain health and obviously motor uh
there's been a lot of competent
intensity which is you know increased
especially from PSU what I understand so
any comment on overall growth we are
targeting in FI26 that is one and second
is a bookkeeping question on the other
income from the non-operating reserves
which seems to be very high uh so
anything on that
so maybe I'll take the first one uh I
think on the growth side
Uh the good part is I think if you look
at some of the actions which are being
taken both at both at various
governments and even our own insurance
regulator I think the efforts have been
very very positive. I think for example
the recent budget did see a lot of a lot
of uh uh people kind of getting a higher
disposable income which kind of augers
well now all of this will start to kind
of play through maybe over the
subsequent uh quarters. So that's a very
very positive action which comes from
the government. Equally, I think
regulators are doing their part in terms
of trying to keep relatively the
interest rate of the environment at far
more acceptable levels and the very
recent rate cuts again kind of augers
well in so far as driving uh consump
retail consumption and in general
driving consumptions are concerned. So,
so there are clearly lot of positive
factors which should aid when it comes
to let's say growth because ours is a
direct reflection of what happens in so
far as economic activities are concerned
and some of these positive actions by
the government and regulators augers
very very well coupled with this I think
if you look at side for the next two
quarters in general I think we are very
very positively placed in terms of how
we see the opportunity play out and also
what we kind of responded to the earlier
question on how the initial corporate
renewal cycle has been. I think that
looks again very very promising. Now
that's something that has started off on
a positive note right from the beginning
of the year. So hence even for the rest
of the year one should see that cycle
play through. So overall I think we are
kind of positively looking at in terms
of how the market should kind of play
out and within that I think what we have
spoken is to try and see how we can
continue to deliver that outperformance
viz with the industry growth numbers is
what we will be kind of penciling in
first two quarters you are absolutely
right uh in nj in terms of the impact of
one by will obviously kind of play out
so maybe to that extent industry growth
could be a little subdued but on a full
year basis I think we are very very
optimistic.
got the part and any uh comment on the
combination guidance uh if you are
changing or revising uh or giving any
new guidance I think we are see on the
guidance part we've given a complete
perspective if the industry continues to
deterate our own belief would be that uh
we are part of the same pond right so uh
you would see uh overall
challenges but in our scheme of things
if there is improvement status quo you
would see us probably uh improving more
importantly it's the ROE part of it
which we would focus on and see what
kind of returns we are able to generate
and in that we've always m maintained
that we want to see at least 16 to you
know 20% kind of a range for us as a
company being given to stakeholders
uh on the bookkeeping on the other
income uh on the non-operating results
usually very high is it something
regrouping or uh if you can
Yeah, nothing specific but it is it is
business as usual for us. They will all
be driven by whatever the regulatory
stipulations are. Uh and uh no no
specific changes per se. Oh thank you.
Thank you ladies and gentlemen. Due to
time constraints we have reached the end
of question and answer session. I would
now like to hand the conference over to
Mr. Sanjiv Mantri for closing comments.
Hi, I think uh great to connect with all
of you. Uh closure of uh another
financial year and uh some exciting
times awaits. Look forward to
interacting with each one of you uh as
and when your time permits. Uh we do
believe that general insurance industry
is poised for a decent year uh going
forward and we would keep in touch and
keep you updated. Thank you so much for
joining in and all the best to each one
of you. Thank you so much.
Thank you on behalf of ICL Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited. That
concludes this conference. Thank you for
joining us. You may now disconnect your
lines.